ngoboards.org 2008-10-02

# Privacy Policy | Global Forum on NGO Governance

  * **Information We Collect**
  * **Sharing Your Information with Third Parties**
  * **User IDs and passwords**
  * **Third Party Links**
  * **Choice**
  * **Security**
  * **Notification of Changes**
  * **Contacting BoardSource**
  * **Special Policy Regarding Information from Children Under Thirteen**

The Global Forum on NGO Governance is a project sponsored by [BoardSource](http://www.boardsource.org/), a nonprofit organization located at 1828 L Street NW, Suite 900, Washington, DC 20036-5114, USA, 202/452-6262. BoardSource (either “we” or “us”), is committed to protecting the privacy of all members and users of the Global Forum on NGO Governance. The following discloses our policy for gathering and disseminating information for this web site located at [www.NGOboards.org](http://www.ngoboards.org/) (the “Site”). If you have any questions about your rights as a member or user of this Site, you may contact, Kathy Hedge, Strategic Initiatives Advisor at khedge [at] boardsource [dot] org. 

_Note:_ This privacy policy only applies to the Site located at [www.NGOboards.org](http://www.ngoboards.org/). This online privacy policy does not apply to the web sites of other companies, individuals, or organizations to which we may provide links. These web sites may have different polices relating to your privacy and information they collect about you. Visitors should consult other sites’ privacy policies, as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or controlled by, third parties. Certain parts of this policy are applicable to members, while other parts apply to non-members. A member is a person that (i) has registered as a member of the Global Forum on NGO Governance web site by completing and submitting the “Become a Member” online form on the Site, and (ii) is in good standing. A non-member is any other person or organization other than a member. For questions on whether you may be a member or a non-member, please contact us. 

### **A. Information We Collect**

We collect two types of information about you when you visit the Site: personal information such as, your name, address, organization, telephone number, and e-mail address, and non-personal, aggregate information (such as information regarding the pages on our Site you have visited and your IP address - the unique identifier of your computer). 

**_1\. Personally Identifiable Information_** The only personally identifying information that we collect and store about you is the information that you have chosen to provide to us. For example, when you register online to become a member, we require that you provide a user name of your choice and an email address, so that you can receive emails from the Site from discussion forums in which you choose to participate. We also may collect your personal information when you contact us via the Site. The Site also enables members, at their option, to create a personal “Profile” page. If you choose to set up such a page, it will be viewable by members of the Site and, when you create such a page, we collect the personal information that you electively choose to provide, including your first and last names, address, title, organization, and other personal information. Note that BoardSource does not use this information except in accordance with Section B, below. You may elect to make your personal Profile page viewable in the Technical Assistance Directory on the Site, which is viewable to both members and nonmembers of the Site. Please do not create a personal Profile if you do not want your information to be collected by BoardSource or shared on the Site. 

****_2\. Non-Personally Identifiable Information._** **We may collect and use non-personally identifiable information about you in the following ways: 

  * Your Internet Protocol (IP) address or the proxy address of your Internet Service Provider (e.g. AOL, CompuServe, Comcast, etc.); 
  * The resource on our server accessed as a result of the request, such as the web page, image, etc.; 
  * The query in the request; 
  * The name and version of your web browser; 
  * The content of any sent or received cookie, as defined below; 
  * The Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) that was accessed before making the request for our web server. ****

****_a. Cookies_** **Some parts of this Site may use a “cookie” – a file placed on your computer hard drive allowing our server to log the pages accessed in the Site to determine if you have visited before. There are two types of cookies: nonpersistent and persistent cookies. A nonpersistent cookie enables a Web site to temporarily store information on your computer as you travel from one page to another. This cookie is automatically deleted from your machine when you close your browser. A persistent cookie is kept even when you close your browser. You can manually delete these cookies using commands specific to your browser and computer system. These cookies store information that would generally not change from visit to visit. The Site uses nonpersistent cookies to retain a member’s login information so that a member can travel to various pages in the Site without the need to re-enter a user ID and password at each new page. The Site uses persistent cookies to automatically log you in when you return to our site. BoardSource only reads cookies written by the Global Forum on NGO Governance Web site. It does not use cookies to obtain information on other Web sites that you may visit. You may set your browser to warn you when placement of a cookie is requested, and decide whether or not to accept it. Please note that by rejecting a cookie some of the features available on the Site may not function properly. ****

****_b. Referrers, IP Addresses and Environmental Variables_** **We may also collect information through “referrers,” IP addresses and various environmental variables. A “referrer” is information the web browser passes along to the www.NGOboards.org web server that references the URL from which you came. An “IP Address” is a number used by computers on a network to identify your computer so that data can be transmitted to you. An “environmental variable” may include, among other things, the domain from which you access the Internet, the time you accessed the web site, the type of web browser and operating system or platform used, the Internet address or the web site you left to visit the web site, the pages you visit while at the web site and the Internet address of the web site you then visit. We may collect IP address information in order to administer the web site and to gather broad demographic information. ****

### ****B. Sharing Your Information with Third Parties****

We may share our members’ and nonmembers’ personally and non-personally identifiable information with third parties that help manage our web site and databases. In addition, we may share your information in order to fulfill a service requested by you. In the unlikely event that all or substantially all of our assets are sold or transferred to another party, we may transfer the personally and non-personally identifiable information of our members and nonmembers to the acquiring entity. We also reserve the right to disclose the personal and non-personal information of our members and nonmembers if we reasonably believe we are required to do so by law; to protect our self or to protect the rights of another user; to reduce the risk of fraud; or to comply with a court order. We will not sell, rent or lend our members’ and nonmembers’ personally identifiable information to any third parties, other than as specifically disclosed in this policy. ** **********  

### ******C. User IDs and passwords******

Each individual registered to use this Site has a unique user ID and password. Users who elect to register on the Site may choose their own user ID; if the user selects a user ID that has already been chosen by another user, the user can select another user ID. This process will continue until the user has selected a unique user ID. Upon registration to the Site, the user will be sent a unique password via email. The user may choose to keep this password, or change it to another password from their personal account page on the Site. Passwords are the private property of the registered user. For reasons of security and privacy, we do not give out passwords to anyone. If you forget your password, you can request that a new password be sent to you. You can change your password at any time from your personal account page on the site. ** ** ************  

### ********D. Third Party Links********

This Site may contain links to other web sites. Additionally, third party sites may from time to time link to the Site. PLEASE BE AWARE THAT WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE CONTENT OR PRACTICES OF ANY OTHER SITES. We encourage our users to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that they visit. Our privacy policy applies solely to the Site, located at [www.NGOboards.org](http://www.ngoboards.org/). ****  

### **********E. Choice**********

We provide you with the following choices regarding the use of your information: 

  * You may choose not to provide us with any personal information; 
  * You may set your browser not to accept cookies, or to warn you when a cookie is being placed on your computer. If you choose not to accept cookies, however, your ability to navigate this Site may be hindered; 
  * If you would like to unsubscribe to any of online forums on this Site, please follow the instructions under the Guidelines and Procedures;
  * If you no longer would like to be a member of the Site, please send us a request to cancel your membership at admin [at] NGOboards [dot] org. 
  * If you would like to change any of the personal information that we have collected about you, please visit your profile page on the Site and follow the prompts from the Membership Management box located in the top right corner of the page. If you need assistance, you may contact us.

### **F. Security.**

We make every effort to have reasonable security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under our control. If you have any questions about the security of our web site, please contact us. ****  

### **G. Notification of Changes**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our privacy policy so you will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by way of e-mail. You will then have a choice as to whether or not we may use your information in this manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. ****  

### **H. Contacting BoardSource**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of the Global Forum on NGO Governance, or any other aspects of this Web site, please contact Kathy Hedge, Strategic Initiatives Advisor at BoardSource at khedge [at] boardsource [dot] org (khedge [at] boardsource [dot] org). All information you provide in any written communication will also be covered by this policy. ****  

### **I. Special Policy Regarding Information from Children Under Thirteen**

We are not targeted to children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from any child under the age of 13 without parental consent. When we receive such information, we delete it as soon as we discover it and do not use it or share it with third parties.

**Effective Date:** June 29, 2007 

|
